Moonage Daydream is a documentary, music film directed by Brett Morgen.
A cinematic odyssey featuring never-before-seen footage
exploring David Bowie's creative and musical journey.
Self (archive footage), played by David Bowie.
Self (archive footage), played by Lou Reed.
Self (archive footage), played by Tina Turner.
Self (archive footage), played by Russell Harty.
Self (archive footage), played by Dick Cavett.
Self (archive footage), played by Mick Ronson.
Moonage Daydream is a 2022 documentary film about English artist David Bowie.
Written, directed, produced and edited by Brett Morgen, the film uses previously
unreleased footage from Bowie's personal archives, including live concert footage.
It is the first film to be officially authorized by Bowie's estate, and
takes its title from the 1972 Bowie song of the same name.
Moonage Daydream had its world premiere at the 2022 Cannes Film
Festival, where it received positive reviews.
It was released theatrically and in IMAX in the
United States on 16 September 2022.
It was shortlisted for Best Documentary Feature at the 95th Academy Awards,
and won Best Music Film at the 66th Annual Grammy Awards.
The film explores themes of rock star, singing,
archive footage, superstar, old footage.